# **Timothy Kroll**

# Senior Software Engineer

**♥** Grand Rapids, MI

≥ teamothykroll@gmail.com

GitHub

in Linkedin

#### **Summary:**

I am a senior developer with 10+ years of software and IT experience building Java and JavaScript applications with React(Router, Hooks), Node, Express, Java Spring, and SQL/NoSQL databases, as well as in a HIPPA-compliant way. I am an ambitious, passionate, and motivated coder and a Product manager.

#### **Skills:**

- ⇒ JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, HTML, CSS, PHP, etc.
- ⇒ React, Redux, Next, Node, Express, Nest, Angular, Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Hibernate, Laravel, etc.
- ⇒ MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL, Firebase, GraphQL, REST API, etc
- ⇒ Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, Git, Unit, Jest, Linux, Github, Scrum

### **Work Experience:**

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Self Employed Jul 2018 - Present

**Stack**: React, Node, Angular, Spring, Microservices, AWS, etc

- Developed web applications for many clients using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node, Spring, etc
- Worked with React Router for developing SPAs
- Involved in creating MongoDB collections documents and developing Mongoose
- Used Jasmine and Karma as end to end testing tools for debugging and software quality assurance.

#### **Project Manager & Senior Software Engineer**

Gordon Food Service Nov 2018 – Jul 2022

**Stack**: Angular, Docker, GCP, Java 11, Kubernetes(K8), Spring Boot

Technology Project Manager maintains vendor relationships and manages the various technology facets for store construction projects. I developed a streamlined RFP process for significant projects utilizing the power of shared Google tools. We have 21 store remodels and 2 new stores actively under construction.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Travelport Jan 2017 - Nov 2018

Stack: React, Node, Nest.js, Java Spring, AWS, Tomcat, Swagger, Active MQ, etc

- Developed and Maintained interactive and dynamic web pages with cross browser compatibility using hand coded semantic HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Bootstrap.
- Server instances on AWS, Tomcat, Swagger were installed and used for deploying Microservices.
- Developed messaging module using Spring JMS, Apache Camel and Active MQ and other services were built using Nest.js, and Spring

#### **Software Engineer**

IndiaNIC Infotech Limited

Aug 2014 – Jan 2017

**Stack**: React, Ajax Hibernate, Javascript, Java Spring, React, Node, Jenkins, Docker, Microservices, etc

- Using Node.js, React.js, Angular to create maintainable single page applications, backed by RESTful web services
- Mentoring other engineers in unit testing and simplifying software architecture

### **Software Developer**

Amway Sep 2012- Jun 2014

Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, Spring MVC, SQL, JDBC, Junit, etc

- Implemented a startup company's expenses management app using AgularJS and Spring
- Developed an online-learning educational app for high schools
- Assisted FE and BE engineers in developing common utilities

### **Telecommunications Specialist**

Gordon Food Service

Jul 2000 - Aug 2010

Unified Communications Administrator. I maintain phone systems for more than 175 stores. I am spearheading the 2022 initiative to bring all stores into compliance with the E911 laws.

#### **Education:**

## Master's degree, Computer science

Calvin University 2008-2012